你是否从此改信基督教？
Do you turn to Christ?
我从此改信基督教
I turn to Christ.
你是否忏悔你的罪过？
Do you repent of your sins?
我忏悔我的罪过
I repent of my sins.
你是否弃恶从善？
Do you renounce evil?
我弃恶从善
I renounce evil.
排练一下 多美的辞藻啊
Rehearsing. Beautiful, isn't it?
圣经的美妙之处就在于用词华丽 什么弃恶从善啊 忏悔罪孽啊
The thing about the Bible is it's so well written. Renounce. Repent.
- 好词 Sue说得对 - 哪个Sue？
- Great words. Sue was right. - Sue?
Sue Lawley 莎士比亚和圣经的那个Sue
Lawley. Shakespeare and the Bible, sort of.
Sue Lawley，曾是BBC Radio 4的广播节目Desert Island Discs的主持人
嘉宾想象自己置身荒岛，选出最想带去的8首歌、一本书，以及一件物品(luxury)
通常供选择的书目有莎士比亚全集、圣经、或者其它宗教哲学类的书
你会带什么物品去荒岛 Peter？
What would your luxury be, Peter?
羽绒被 或者果酱 快点问我选什么歌
Duvet. Maybe marmalade. And the music - go on, ask me what's the music.
- 你会选什么歌？ - 八首全是朱塞佩·威尔第 知道为什么吗？
- What's the music, Peter? - Eight straight Verdis. Why?
Giuseppe Verdi，意大利作曲家\n他和理查德·瓦格纳一起被认为是19世纪最有影响力的歌剧创作者
- 为什么？- 我来告诉你
- Why? - I'll tell you.
- 你说 - 因为听威尔第的时候 灵魂会跟着音乐一起升华
- You tell us. - Because you soar. You soar with Mr V.
莎士比亚 圣经 威尔第 生活 都能让人升华
Shakespeare, the Bible, Giuseppe V. Life.
- 你会是一个好教父的 - 我会是一个好教父
- You're gonna be a very good godfather. - I'm gonna be a very good godfather.
别人的教父跟我比都相形见绌 你俩算是选对人了
Other godfathers will weep when they see how good I am. You chose right, both of you.
- 绝对 - 必须
- Absolutely. - Absolutely.
♪ Don't you ever stop long enough to start?
♪ Get your car out of that gear
我叫Yuri Gagarin 我无家可归
I'm homeless and my name is Yuri Gagarin.
- Yuri Gagarin不是那个宇航员吗？ - 苏联英雄
- The astronaut? - And hero of Soviet Union.
Yuri Gagarin，尤里·加加林， 苏联航天员，世界上第一个进入太空的地球人
案发当时我正在帕克广场小憩
I'm having a bit of a lie-down in Park Square.
身边坐着几个正在吃烤熟菜跟抹着山羊奶酪面包的人
Blending in not very well with the roasted vegetables and goat's- cheese-on-ciabatta classes.
- 这时候 - 面对这样一位耐心、单良、聪慧的律师
- When all of a sudden... - For no reason I've been able to articulate
我自己也无法解释为什么我突然会
to my patient, kind, actually rather brilliant barrister,
拿起其中一个人的手机 反复用脚狠跺 你觉得会怎么判？
I grab some man's mobile phone and stamp on it a lot. What do you think?
- 法官是谁？ - Martin
- Judge? - Martin.
他唯一只会对无动机的盲目暴力犯罪加以严惩 依我看九个月监禁吧
The only thing he's heavy on - motiveless mindless violence. Nine months for Yuri.
给我来份香辣咖喱鸡 喂 你说
Chicken vindaloo. Yeah, what is it?
再来点薄饼 你想要女律师？ 那就Wendy de Souza
Poppadoms. You want a woman? I'll give you Wendy de Souza.
绝对是数一不数二的女中豪杰
Best Doris in a wig there is.
四片烤饼 抹点芒果酸辣酱 好 挂了
Four naan. Mango chutney. Yeah, later.
还有白饭 不要米里掺东西的那种
Plain rice. None of that bits-in-shit.
小强 赌一把点差
Johnny Boy. Spread bet.
就赌Bob带外卖回来的时间 我说十二到十五分钟之间
Bob's return from the Bengal Lancers. Spread of 12 to15 minutes.
什么是点差？
What's a spread bet?
Peter对某件事给出一个区间 随便什么都能拿来赌 我跟他意见对峙
Peter says what he reckons on whatever and I say no.
只要超过了他说的区间 就算我赢 能赢多少就看量上超了多少
And whatever more it is, or less than he says, then I win by the amount increasing,
或者时间上差了多少
by the time he's wrong by less or more.
但如果在他说的区间范围内 我的赌注他就能赢走
But, if he's on a no's, within the spread, and he takes whatever I put on the table.
真没意思
This is a very frightening rule.
两份半咖喱鸡块 三份焗饭 一升可乐
Two and a half chicken tikka masala, three pilau rice and a litre of Coke.
- 赌不赌 小强？ - 好啊 一百块
- You up for it, Johnny Boy? - Yeah, go on. 100.
咱们事务所收入两百万 你有百分之二十的提成 才赌一百块也太少了吧
Chambers turns over two million, you're on 20%. 100 seems a bit cheap, doesn't it?
- 那就一千 - 买定离手
- A grand. - Excellent.
计时开始
Go.
我这个数二不数一的女律师有什么案子吗 Peter？
Anything for the second-best Doris in a wig, Peter?
- 你荷尔蒙恢复了 小姐？ - 没事了
- How's the hormones, Miss? - Fine.
- 有人不高兴了 - 我真的好了 Peter
- She snapped. - Fine, Peter.
- 谋杀案 - 什么谋杀案？
- Murder. - What kind of murder?
- 精液 - 谋杀精液？
- Seminal. - Seminal murder?
seminal指精液\n也有意义重大、影响深远的意思
一招定乾坤的大案子
The kind of murder that could change everything.
能让我们事务所前途无量
Here. Us.
成败在此一举 Rose 当事人今晚过来
It's a life-or-death murder, Rose. Con here tonight.
- 谁带我？ - 说反了
- Who's leading me? - Wrong way round.
- 我带谁？- 随你挑
- Who am I leading? - You choose.
找不到钱包了
Wallet. Can't find it.
给
There you are.
我新接到一起谋杀案
I've got a brand-new murder, just come in.
不错啊 什么谋杀
Good. What kind of murder?
被告是那种人啊
That kind of murder.
- Billy - Rose\n- Billy. - Rose.
- 你有点 - 我怎么了？
- You're being a bit... - What?
呃 疏远我
Well, away from me.
是因为你的庭审吗
Is it your trial?
是啊
Yeah.
我这个案子需要带一个低级律师
I need a junior. In my murder.
好啊
Right.
Billy
Billy.
- 你说我是低级律师？ - 称谓而已
- Junior? - In name only.
咱俩平等还不行吗 这案子能让你暂时不去胡思乱想
Equal partners. A good murder will take your mind off...
想什么？ 想我可能做不成律师？ 想我可能会被判刑？
Mind off what? The end of my career? Prison sentence?
想我在牢里可能再也见不到Daneil可爱的笑容？
The 400 bloody fantastic smiles from Daniel that won't reach me in prison?
对不起
Sorry.
我是谋杀案 你呢？
Murder. You?
也是谋杀案
Murder.
我进来干啥来着？ 我完全想不起来我来干啥了
Why am I in here? I've completely forgotten why I came in here.
- 你好 亲爱的 - 亲爱的 你好
- Hello, darling. - Hello, darling.
想起来了 关于Martin法官的传言是真的吗？
I remember. Is it true about Judge Martin?
- 什么传言？ - 说他会严惩暴力犯
- What about him? - That he's not keen on violence.
- 干嘛问我 - 我猜你也许会知道
- Why are you asking me? - I thought you might know the answer.
- 需要我泡杯茶吗？ - 不用了 谢谢
- Can I get anyone a cup of tea? - No, thanks.
好的 我要 谢谢
Yes. Tea, please.
- 他叫Hussein - 我的实习律师
- Hussein. - My new pupil.
- 这对他太不公平了 - 怎么了？
- Oh, that's unfair on him. - What?
明知道所里只有一个名额 还找两个实习生
Giving him a pupillage when everyone knows there's only one place up for grabs in chambers.
不是人人都喜欢Morag的 Rose
Morag isn't everyone's taste, Rose.
他挺好的 勤奋刻苦 认真钻研 对这行是真爱
He's a good thing. Hard-working, good researcher. Loves the law.
- 那么勤奋还有闲工夫给大家泡茶？ - 什么意思？
- Still has time to make a cup of tea? - Meaning?
他拍马屁的时候有多甜？
How many sugars are there in "sycophant"?
- 嗨 我是Hussein Ali - 我是Morag Black
- Hi. Hussein Ali. - Morag Black.
- 你就是另外那个实习律师 - 另一个实习律师就是我
- You're the other pupil. - Yes. The other pupil.
- 你导师是Rose Fitzgerald吧？ - 是 你呢？
- Rose Fitzgerald's, right? - Yes. You?
我跟Tom Mitford
Tom Mitford.
- Rose很棒 她非常 - 她是红人吗？
- Rose is great. She's very... - Is she a big player?
- 什么？ - 她是所里的大人物吗
- What? - In chambers.
嗯 呃 我觉得是吧 她一直都
Erm... Well, yes, I suppose she is. She's always...
她喝茶爱加糖吗？
Does she take sugar?
对 两勺
Yes. Two.
已经过了十四分钟了 再过一分钟我就赢了
14 minutes gone. 60 seconds and I start winning.
- 赢什么？ - 赢大钱
- Winning what? - Vast amounts of cash.
重婚罪 十二点之后开庭 你有足够的时间先处理踩手机的案子
Bigamy. Not before 12. Time for you to get shot of your mobile-phone rage first.
还剩二十秒喽
20 seconds to go.
保释申请 地方法院
Bail app. Magistrates'.
十五秒耶
15 seconds.
保释申请 皇家法庭 欢迎一游
Bail app. Crown Court. Welcome.
- 如果你愿意 我可以帮你看看 - 不用了 只是保释申请而已
- I'll look at it for you if you like. - It's OK. It's only a bail app.
八秒 七秒 六秒 五秒
Eight, seven, six, five...
三秒 两秒
...three, two...
- 吃的来了 - 我了个大去
- Grub up. - Bloody hell!
我了个大大大去
Bloody, bloody, bloody hell.
我去见新来的大才子去了
I'm off to see the most talented newcomers in town.
- 什么才子？ - 犯罪才子
- Talented what? - Criminals.
Frank Green跟他的兄弟们 有天赋 彪悍 刚起家 有点像我们事务所
Frank Green and brothers. Gifted, heavy, new. Like us, really.
- 你选哪个低级律师？ - Billy
- Who's your junior gonna be? - Billy.
- 好吧 - 好吧是什么意思 Peter
- Right. - Meaning, Peter?
沉着 可靠 稳重 低级律师的特质应有尽有
Stable, reliable, steady. Everything a good junior should be.
我得先填一填肚子 小姐
Have to line the stomach, Miss.
- 因为你要去喝酒 - 因为我要去喝酒
- Because you're going drinking. - Because I'm going drinking.
跟Peter一起 我猜还有一个事务律师
With him. And don't tell me,a brand-new solicitor
如果你们酒灌的够多 又能把他拉拢过来
who could be very tasty for us if enough drink is poured on him.
为了律师行成天以酒为伴 你以为我们容易吗 小姐
It's not easy, Miss, having to drink all the time for the sake of chambers.
不过另一个人倒不是事务律师 是个重刑犯
It's not a solicitor, though. It's heavy criminals, Miss.
怪不得我的当事人到现在还不来见我
Which explains why Mr Green is late for his conference with me.
原来是跟我的高级书记官畅饮去了
He's out having a quite half-shandy with my senior clerk.
听说你让Rose Fitzgerald给Frank出庭辩护
I've been told Rose Fitzgerald's the brief you put up for Frank.
没错
Yeah.
她做得来吗？ 恕我直言 我可见识过那些女律师是怎样的
Can she hack it? No offence, but I've seen these women briefs
细声细语 比绣花还磨叽
be classy and cut glass and all that steel knickers with a Rolex and all that shit
什么样的都有
and it's never the same, not really.
她到底会不会让Frank满意？
Is Frank gonna feel she's gonna eat meat in there for him and then come back for more?
证人跟Rose当面对峙 当正式开庭时
One to one, witness in the box, Rose on her feet. When it really counts...
她会杀个片甲不留
...she savages them.
你跟Fitzgerald约好的 已经迟到了 Frank
You're late for Miss Fitzgerald, Frank.
- 那是 - Frank Green
- That's... - Frank Green.
他是我的第一位当事人
My first-ever client.
- 谋杀犯 - 只是疑犯而已
- A murderer. - Allegedly.
他还送过我一瓶香槟
He sent me champagne.
- 你怎么知道他叫什么？ - 模拟法庭的时候用过他的案子
- How do you know his name? - R versus Green.
因为拘留期限 他都已经被写进法案录了
Custody time limits. He's in the Law Reports.
当时由于没有在拘留期限内开庭 所以他被保释了
He got bail because they hadn't brought him to trial quickly enough.
什么东西眨眼跟打炮像老虎一样猛？
What winks and fucks like a tiger?
- 最低工资 - 什么？
- The minimum wage. - What?
这是所有实习律师应得的
We were going to get it. All pupils.
上诉法庭却驳回这一条
And then the Court of Appeal said no.
- 我在想 - 想什么？
- I was thinking of... - What?
不应该这样 凭什么小强能输得起一千块钱
It's not right. Why should Johnny Boy be capable of losing £1,000
我们却只能省吃俭用地生活
when the rest of you and I scraping around for...
你想说什么？
You were thinking what?
我们事务所是与时俱进的
We're a progressive set of chambers.
我认为不管上诉法庭怎么说 事务所都应该付给我们最低工资
I think they should be giving it to us, whatever the Court of Appeal says.
- 我回去了 - 回事务所？
- I'm going back. - To chambers?
- 都六点半了 - 我休息好了可以再战
- It's half-past six. - I get a second wind.
希望我们能做朋友 我明白咱俩是竞争关系
I hope we can be friends. I know we're in competition and all that,
不过还是应该友好竞争
but... we should be friends.
你挣多少钱？
How much money do you earn?
很多
A lot.
- 那McLeish呢？ - 更多
- And McLeish? - More than a lot.
更多是多少？
Meaning?
别说是我告诉你的 所有报酬的百分之十
Don't tell him I told you. 10% of all fees.
光是过去半年 事务所的收入就有一百万英镑
Incoming fees for the last six months? £ 1 million.
他一年能挣二十万？
200,000 a year?
不过大部分都贡献给所里的业务消遣开销了
A lot of it goes on... corporate entertainment.
来杯玛格丽特吗 Black小姐？
Can I get you a margarita, Miss Black?
一起出庭的还有Billy Guthrie
I'm giving you Billy Guthrie, too.
两个人我给你打七五折
Two fuck-offs for the price of one and a half.
- 你有我有全都有 - 有什么？
- We've both got them, you and me. - What?
- 这两匹良驹 - 除此之外呢？
- Stables packed full of talent. - And?
我知道你想要什么 你想知道今后你的每一位被告
And I know what you want. Every time one of your boys is up in court,
都是哪个律师替他们辩护
you wanna know who you're getting to look after him,
你希望他们都能言善辩 而且都来自同一家你信得过的事务所
that it comes from a place you can trust, and that every brief's a fighter.
不止 我还要他们懂得乖乖听话
It's a bit more than that. I want briefs who do what they're told.
我说被告是清白的 那他就是清白的
If I say defence is mistaken ID, then mistaken ID it is.
不能有异议 不要有自己的小想法
No arguments. No frolics of their own.
那就要看话跟话之间怎么说了
That's a communications thing from you to me to them.
是看你有没有本事让他们听你的话
It's about control. It's about keeping it tight.
- 那这个案子 - 搞错人了 Peter
- This murder... - Mistaken ID, Peter.
指认Frank的证人搞错了
Witness picked Frank and he's wrong.
我已经跟Frank谈好辩词了
I've communicated to Frank what his defence is.
剩下就看你跟你那两个律师谈了 就这么简单
You communicate to your pair. Simple.
对你来说应该就跟和Stevie谈案子一样 她是个很棒的事务律师
It's like with Stevie. She's a great solicitor.
她会先让客户先表达自己的想法 然后表示赞同
She lets us express ourselves and then expresses what we express.
你希望我们三方一起合作
And you wanna make you and her into a triangle with me.
我们需要更多的了解彼此 才能紧密合作 无懈可击
We'd have to be close. We'd have to know a lot about each other and be watertight, the three of us.
- 你跟Stevie的合作就很紧密 不是吗 - 我们这算是谈成了吗？
- You and Stevie are solid, aren't you? - Is this an offer?
我还在考虑另外一家事务所
I'm looking at one other set of chambers.
- 哪家？ - 书记官叫Marlowe
- Who? - Clerk called Marlowe.
考虑好了我会告诉你的
I'll let you know.
我得走了
I've got to go.
我真的得走了
I've really got to go.
我要高潮了 要来了 来了 来了
I'm coming. I'm coming. I'm coming. I'm coming!
我要来了 来了
I'm coming! I'm coming!
我走了
I'm going.
- 去哪？ - 见当事人
- Where? - Con.
跟谁一起？
With who?
- 吃醋了？ - 才没有
- Jealous? - No.
- 你有 - 我有
- Yes. - Yes.
Rose Fitzgerald
Rose Fitzgerald.
你不能孤注一掷 Alex
Never a good idea to put all your eggs in one basket, Alex.
别
Don't.
- 别什么？ - 别不高兴
- What? - Sulk.
- 我才没有 - 我听得到
- I'm not. - I can hear it.
我知道不高兴听起来啥样的 听
I know what sulking sounds like. Listen.
某人不高兴的声音
The sound of a boy sulking.
我才没有不高兴
I'm completely not sulking.
Billy也一起
And Billy.
Billy和Rose？ 两个我最好的朋友？
Billy and Rose? My best friend and my best friend?
你刚刚是在撅嘴吗 Hay先生？
Is that a pout, Mr Hay?
当事人都到了 Stevie还没来？
Client's here. No sign of our Stevie?
我可以先去帮忙 在事务律师过来之前做做记录
I'd be happy to sit in. Take notes till the solicitor gets here.
Morag呢？ 最好让她做记录 她呃...
Where's Morag? Morag would be better. She's erm...
我更她更熟一些 有看到她么？
We know each other. Have you seen her?
没
No.
- 那好吧 你来 - 没问题
- OK. Fine. - No problem.
被害人全身上下所有有洞的地方全都被插满了烧烫了的织线针
"The victim had heated knitting needles inserted into every orifice -
眼睛里 鼻孔里 嘴巴里
his eyes, his nostrils, his mouth..."
还有后庭
His anal passage.
有意思
Funny.
有意思？
Funny?
没人用这个词
Nobody speaks like that.
又不是警方声明 经验之谈
Except in police statements. In my experience.
后什么庭啊
Anal passage? My arse.
他当时还没死 他承受的痛苦超出我的想象
"He wasn't dead yet. He was in more agony than I thought possible."
我不是那种你不做声光靠沉默就能逼我开口的人 Rose
I've never been the kind of boy to fill in a girl's silence, Rose.
听我说 不是我做的 Rush先生认错人了 误会总是难免的
Listen. It wasn't me. Mr Rush got it wrong. Mistake. It happens.
而且坦白讲 我怎么会做出这么低端的事情
And frankly, it's ludicrous to suggest I'd do a thing like that.
这种事情是小罗罗干的 我可不是什么小罗罗
It's... something the boys do. And I'm more than a boy.
总的来说 Green先生
On the whole, Mr Green,
我太高端了这种事情不会亲为 这样的辩词陪审团不会买账的
juries don't much go for the "I'm too heavy a villain to get my hands dirty" defence.
你说的对 简洁明了
You're right. Nice and simple.
没有法医取证 就只有你跟证人
There's no forensics. It's a classic one-on-one.
一对一
You and the witness.
让陪审团相信证人搞错了 然后我无罪释放 就这样照做
Show the jury how he got it wrong and we're out of there. Simple.
这可是我见过的最简洁明了的嫌犯自述
It's one of the best descriptions I've seen of a suspect.
这是险棋 Frank 符合你的作风 我们可以说是别人栽赃嫁祸
It's very close, Frank. It's very you. I think we should look at fit-up.
人人都知道你们Green家跟Fleck家在争地盘
Everyone knows there's a turf war - Greens versus Flecks.
里兹最大的两个犯罪家族
The two biggest crime families in Leeds.
这事很容易说成是Fleck家对你栽赃嫁祸 对吧
This could so easily be a Fleck fit-up, couldn't it?
大概吧
I think it could.
- Fleck家族 - 他们家怎么了？
- The Flecks. - What about them?
你们两家之间到底什么问题
Where are you... at, them and you?
他们惧怕我们Green家 他们不懂我们
They're scared of the Green family. They don't understand us.
他们家族掌控了这个城市三十年 靠巧取豪夺才搞来那么一点钱
They've spent 30 years running this city, doing armed blags for a few grand.
老掉牙的虚张声势
Knocking about with Barbara Windsor lookalikes.
接着我们家族崛起了
And now we're here.
不同于他们那种犯犯罪养养鸟的疲软作风 我们要犀利得多
And we're a lot sharper than "I do crime but I've got a lot of budgies."
就是这样 他们不明白
That's what. They don't understand.
所以他们慌神了 不过这案子的重点不是这个
So they are scared. But it's not that here.
而是平民百姓Gary Rush犯了一个他自认为正确的错误 认错人了
Gary Rush is a genuine member of the public, making a genuine mistake. I am the wrong man.
我认为这不是最佳辩词
I'm not sure it's the best defence.
我们就用这个辩词 懂了吗
It's the one we're running. OK?
我想让Morag从明天开始全程跟这件案子
I want Morag on this. Full time. From tomorrow.
她十点半要上庭做保释申请
She's got a bail app at 10:30.
别管什么保释申请了 我自己的案子需要我自己的实习律师
Dump the bail app. I want my own pupil on this.
Stevie 那边没事 他们搞的定 我得跟你谈谈
Stevie, it's alright. They don't need you. I want to talk to you.
你有看到Alex吗？
Have you seen Alex?
- 是啊 他 - 先别说
- Yeah, he's... - No.
什么？
What?
- 她是 - 是她
- That's... - Yeah.
- 嗨 Peter Alex在所里吗？ - 不知道
- Hi, Peter. Alex still in chambers? - I don't know.
- 那我进去看看 - 好
- I'll erm... pop in and have a look. - OK.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hi. - Hi.
这案子很明显应该用...
This case is sitting up and begging to be run...
- 我们已经收到指示了 - 谁的指示?
- We've got our instructions. - From who?
Frank Green 当事人 他说这不是别人栽赃嫁祸
Frank Green. The client. Who says it's not a fit-up.
- 还有你刚刚那是什么意思？ - 怎么了？
- What was all that about, anyway? - What?
用念恐怖故事一样的语气陈述案情 还用那种眼神盯着当事人
All that reading out the horror and staring at the client.
- 我喜欢看着当事人的眼睛 - 为什么 他们都是有罪的
- I like to look them in the eye. - Why? They're always guilty.
- 也许吧 但我就是喜欢看 - 什么时候开始的？
- Maybe. But I like to look. - Since when?
自从有了孩子
Since the baby.
自从有了Daniel
Since Daniel.
你好
Hello.
- 嗨 - 我来那啥
- Hi. - I was just...
- 我跟你说这些干啥？ - 说什么？
- Why am I telling you this? - Telling me what?
我来拿我的案情陈述 这事显然不需要特意跟你说
I was gonna say I was just gonna pick up my brief, which I really don't need to say to you
因为我就在这上班 我当然可以来拿我的陈述
because I work here, so I'm allowed to... pick up my brief.
抱歉 天哪 快停下
Sorry. God. Shut up.
你来干啥？
You?
我？ 呃 那个 我
Me? Er... Well, I was just erm...
随便啦
Whatever.
Tom
Tom.
- 你的案情陈述 - 哦 对 多谢提醒
- Your brief. - Oh, yeah. Thanks.
再见
Bye.
Alex
Alex.
喂
Hi.
还没 你在哪呢？
No, no. Where are you?
哦 好吧
Ah, right.
因为你手机关机了 所以
It's just your er... ...mobile was off, so...
- 我去过苏格兰 - 苏格兰哪里？
- Yeah, I went to Scotland once. - Where?
- 去钓鱼 - 去哪钓鱼？
- Fishing. - Where?
巴特里\n(格拉斯哥一家足球俱乐部)
Partick Thistle.
怎么了 笑什么
What? What?
我的两个实习律师都很好 自信 可靠 不是那种乳臭未干的无知青年
I've got two good pupils - confident, reliable, not the usual wet-behind-the-ears material.
我可付不起他们两个人的工资
I can't afford to pay them to go to the Mags' for me.
- 如果他们不要钱你就能付得起了 - 什么？
- You can if they're free. - What?
你给我们介绍了像Frank Green这样的大案子 我欠你一个人情
You've started to bring us some big work, like Frank Green. I think we owe you.
我打算让我的实习律师免费帮你打理Mag那边的工作
I'm prepared to cover all your Mags' work with my pupils for nothing.
我希望巩固你我之间的合作
I want us to be a solid thing, you and me.
- 你有什么要求？ - 你把大案子都给我们做
- And in return? - You bring all your big work to us.
不要给Michael Marlowe他们
And not to Michael Marlowe.
我刚说的就是这个意思
That is implied in the logic I've been using.
- 那你的实习律师呢？ - 他们很棒 我都说了
- What about your pupils? - They're good. I told you.
我是说 没钱他们怎么生活
I mean... how are they going to survive?
我们最终只会雇用他俩的其中一个
One of them will be taken on, one won't.
他们在竞争 所以谁都不会挑三拣四 这点他们心里清楚
They're in competition. Neither of them can afford to kick up. They know that.
- 让我再想想 - 想好了告诉我
- I'll think about it. - Let me know.
- 想好告诉你 - 很好
- I'll let you know. - Good.
同意了
The answer's yes.
两件事
Two things.
第一 你是书记官 她是律师 你的咸猪手离她远点
One, you're a clerk and she's not. Hands off wee Morag.
- 第二 - 这是什么？
- Two. - What's this?
你输给我的一千块钱 你知道伊索吗？
The grand you lost. You ever heard of Aesop?
- 知道 有点像国际刑警 对吧 - 伊索寓言
- Yeah, bit like Interpol, aren't they? - Fables.
寓言？ 我想想
Fables. Right.
寓言就是有寓意的小故事
Stories with a moral.
现在这则故事的寓意就是不要在赌马者养的马身上下赌注
The moral of this story is don't bet on horses owned by the bookie.
这事我挺生气的 Peter
I'm a bit pissed, Peter.
Bob和我是家人 他妈是我妹妹
Bob and me. Family. He's my sister's kid.
- 他是你弟弟？ - 侄子 有没有搞错
- He's your brother? - Nephew. Jesus.
所以你是故意的？
And you fixed it?
Bob跟印度人那边也是你故意安排的？
You fixed it with Bob and the Indian?
这事说明了Bob对我们事务所和我们书记官有多重要
It's an illustration of how useful Bob can be to us and the clerks room.
没人知道他是我侄子
Nobody knows about the nephew thing.
Bob是我们的眼线 在外面打探消息
Bob's gonna be a mole.  Someone people let things drop in front of.
然后再回来向你报告
And then he reports back to you.
我是个正人君子 小强 你应该懂的
I'm a man of honour, Johnny boy. You should've known that by now.
- 别跟自己人过不去 - 好的
- You don't fuck your own. - OK.
还有 书记官和实习律师不要乱搞
Er... Clerks and pupil-barristers do not mix.
要搞去跟自己同行搞 小强 我就说这么多
Fuck your own, Johnny Boy. Fuck your own. That's my advice.
- 无犯罪能力 - 莱斯丽·嘉芮特才对
- Doli incapax. - Lesley Garrett, actually.
Doli incapax是"incapable of crime"的拉丁语\n该准则认为不满十岁的儿童无需对其所犯下的罪行承担刑事责任\nBilly以为Rose在说歌剧的演唱者
拉丁语 假设儿童无法分辨
The presumption that children don't know the difference
顽皮跟犯罪的区别
between naughtiness and er... criminality. Latin.
Frank Green曾几何时就跟他一样
And this was Frank Green, once upon a time.
咱儿子将来要当神经外科医生兼国际球星 你居然把他跟那个疯子相提并论
That's my son, the neurosurgeon and international footballer you're comparing to a mindless lunatic.
人人都经历过孩童时期 不谙世事 然后
Everyone's a baby. Doli incapax. And then...
一半的孩子长大成了男人
Half the babies turn into men.
- Billy - 什么事 Rose
- Billy. - Yes, Rose?
- 上庭好运 - 好 对了 Rose
- Good luck today. - Yeah. Er, Rose.
- 什么事 Billy - 上庭好运
- Yes, Billy? - Good luck today.
那是Fleck家的人 过来围观一下
Fleck family, showing a passing interest.
首先 我们需要使Gary Rush对你的指认不成立
Step one, try and exclude the evidence of\nGary Rush picking you out of a group ID.
如果这事进展顺利 我敢打赌不会有正式庭审 你会无罪释放
If that goes our way, my money says no trial, you walk.
- 如果不顺利呢？ 其次
- And if it doesn't go our way? - Step two.
盘问环节把他往死里问 问到大家相信他认错人了 简单
Cross-examine Gary Rush into the ground on how he's wrong about it being you he saw. Simple.
- 再然后呢？ - 你就能庆祝胜利了
- Step three? - You kiss and hold her tightly.
你怎么无处不在
How do you do that - get everywhere?
精灵 小叮当 排期官 都是天生的会到处乱跑
Puck. Tinkerbell. List officer. It's in the genes.
我就不信你找不出来几个跟Frank Green哪怕有一点点相似的人
I can't believe you couldn't find a line-up of men a bit like Frank Green.
西约克郡找几个看着像坏人的人应该没那么难吧
The violent-bastard look is not so uncommon in West Yorkshire.
私下跟你坦白 你说的对 排选比群选安全多了
I think you're right, off the record. ID parades are so much safer than group IDs.
没关系的 Hussein 你可以问我什么是群选 我不会鄙视你的
It's all right, Hussein. You can ask me what a group ID is. I won't think any less of you.
Morag 你来解释一下
Morag.
如果你找不到足够的人进行排选
If you can't get a proper ID parade together,
警察会把犯罪嫌疑人置于拥挤的公共场合
the police can take the suspect to a crowded public place,
然后让证人从人群中找出嫌疑人
put the witness there too and ask the witness to pick out the suspect if they can.
是啊 这我知道 还是谢了
Yeah, I know. But, thanks.
- 这次的指认是在哪进行的 Stevie - 弗雷泽商场
- Where did they hold this one, Stevie? - House of Fraser.
通往三层的扶梯上
On the escalator going up to the third floor.
Morag 帮我做件事 现在去一趟弗雷泽商场
Morag, I want you to do something for me. Go to the House of Fraser...
我迟到了 迟得太狠了
Late. Very, very late.
- 上午好Tom - Gagarin先生
- Morning, Tom. - Mr Gagarin?
Yuri Gagarin在吗
Is Yuri Gagarin here?
- 我这名字是通过合法渠道改的 - 改得好
- Changed my name by deed poll. - Oh. Good. Excellent.
- Mitford先生 - 改名字是因为那个航天员 对吧？
- Mr Mitford. - This is a space thing, right?
- 太空(空间)什么的最赞了 - 没错
- That's what this is about. Space. - Yes.
- 我十二点还有个重婚案 - 上午好 Tom
- I've got a bigamy at 12. - Morning, Tom.
Fleck先生 像您这种肚大无脑的汉子用这种眼神盯着我
Mr Fleck, I've been fielding the moronic stares
我都见怪不怪了
of men with big bellies and no brains for an awfully long time.
所以请收起您那套无聊的把戏
Why don't you spare us all the tedium of your cartoon personality?
空间
Space.
法官大人 被告的行为是对空间的需求
Your Honour, it's about space.
Gagarin先生损毁的手机的主人占据了过多的空间
The owner of the mobile phone destroyed by Mr Gagarin takes up a lot of it.
虽然他身高只有一米六七 体形也中等
He's only five foot five and he's of medium build,
但他当时穿了一件很惹人嫌的外套 让人看着碍眼
but he wears very noisy suits and his loudness makes him... not small.
- 什么外套？ - 条纹外套
- Suits? - Pinstripes.
条纹之间的空隙很大
The ones with the big gaps between the stripes.
- 啊 最难看的那种条纹 - 他太惹人注意了
- Ah, the noisiest stripe of all. - He screams his presence.
案发当日 他坐在公园长椅上
On the day in question, he stood in Park Square
大声的打着电话
and made a big, fat phone call.
当然这对公园里的鸽子和松鼠没什么影响
The pigeons didn't mind. The squirrels were OK.
但是我的当事人Yuri Gagarin先生当时正在他身边睡觉
But Yuri Gagarin was asleep, practically at his feet.
因为Gagarin先生是流浪汉
Because Mr Gagarin is homeless
他无家可归
and because he has no space of his own to inhabit,
这位手机的主人便得出了一个错误的结论
the owner of the mobile phone made a presumption.
他认为Gagarin可以被无视
He presumed that Mr Gagarin... didn't exist.
这个想法对谁来说都是无法容忍的
And that, in anyone's terms, is an outrageous presumption.
之所以踩烂手机 是因为手机主人在Gagarin先生的"卧室"里
The phone got stamped on because its owner used it with customary loudness
肆无忌惮的大声讲电话
in Mr Gagarin's bedroom.
Gagarin先生 请起立
Stand up, Mr Gagarin.
我向来反对无端暴力行为
I don't like mindless violence.
我刚接触这件案子的时候 第一反映就是无端暴力
"Mindless" was the word in my head when I saw these papers.
但Mitford先生却用愤怒、压抑、沮丧等字眼偷换概念
Mr Mitford has replaced that word with others - rage, oppression and frustration.
如果我依然认为这是无端暴力行为
If "mindless" was still the word in my head...
你就会被判监禁
...you would be going to prison.
如果我认为不是 你就不用蹲牢
It's not and you're not.
你可以谢谢Mitford先生了 应该大谢
You can thank Mr Mitford for that. Make sure you do.
我判处你一年内有条件释放
Conditional discharge for 12 months.
- 他是谁？ - Gary Rush
- Who's that? - Gary Rush.
他就是证人啊 指认你的人
That's our man, the man who described you.
说不定是你失散已久的双胞胎弟弟
Or your long-lost twin brother.
- 下面去搞定重婚案 - 好好搞
- On to bigamy. - Have fun.
重婚罪先生？ 对不起 抱歉 真抱歉
Mr Bigamy? Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
呃 Jones先生
Erm, Mr Jones.
上午十点的商场 人很多
Ten o'clock in the morning. Very busy shop.
扶梯也是满的 各色人都有
A full escalator. A good mix of people.
这种情况很适合进行身份指认
Ideal conditions for a fair identification procedure.
证人Rush先生站在电梯上方的尽头
The witness, Mr Rush, stands at the top of the escalator,
用两分钟的时间看着人们上电梯
looking down at a range of people coming up over a two-minute period?
是的
Yes.
Frank Green正是其中之一
And one of those people blended in with everyone else is Frank Green?
没错
That's correct.
人群是否足够混合 对认证环节至关重要 探长
The blending-in process is vital to the fairness of the procedure, Inspector.
当然
Absolutely.
你们使用的是几层通往几层的电梯？
From which floor to which floor does the escalator you were using run?
二层通往三层
The second to the third.
- 我最爱乘的一段电梯 - 你说什么？
- My favourite journey. - Sorry?
这电梯通往女士内衣层
The ride up to women's lingerie.
也有很多男士 我们常常用这段扶梯来进行指认
There are plenty of men. It's a location we use a lot.
男女的比例很协调
There is a good mix of both men and women.
丈夫也会去为夫人买内衣 探长
Husbands buying presents for their wives, Inspector.
正是如此
That kind of thing.
那我们开始看录像 探长
Here we go, Inspector.
中年妇女 又是中年妇女
Ann Widdecombe. Ann Widdecombe again.
瘦模特 嗑药的瘦模特 白领女士
Underweight model, underweight model on heroin, Norma Major,
哦 出现了一个穿着皮夹克 三天没刮胡子的男人
and, oh, look, a great big man with three-day stubble and a leather jacket.
会不会就是他呢
Could that be the one?
不好说 不过我觉得有可能
Tough to say. But on balance, I think it might be him.
这种人群的混合方式你居然也说是合理的？
Fair and proper, Inspector?
探长？
Blended?
没话说了吧 混蛋
Snookered, you bastard.
肃静 Green先生 否则就请你出去了
Be quiet, Mr Green, or I'll pot you.
我的裁决认定这样的指认条件不符合要求
My ruling is that this identification procedure was unsatisfactory.
本次指证结果不成立
The evidence will be excluded.
但是考虑到Rush先生的证词
But the description of the man who killed the victim
关于被告的描述非常精准
was so good and accurate in Mr Rush's statement
即使没有合理指证的条件下
that we don't need the identification evidence to proceed.
- 本案依然要进行正式庭审 - 傻逼
- There's going to be a trial. - Dickhead.
Green先生 等这件案子结束之后
At the end of this trial, Mr Green,
我打算去玩玩高尔夫 自家花园里休闲娱乐娱乐
I'm going to play a little golf, spend the weekend in Venice,
周末再去威尼斯渡个假
a lot of time in my garden.
而你 如果输了这官司 就准备在监狱里安享晚年吧
If you go down for this, you'll be spending your entire life in a ten-by-ten.
你再想想 到底谁才是傻逼
Now, then, Mr Green... which one of us is the dickhead?
案发后Rush报警的电话记录
The record of the 999 call that Rush made when he reported this -
我能看一下吗
could we have it, please?
谢了
Thank you.
这是Rush打电话报警的手机号
The mobile number here - this is Rush calling 999.
给我一份报警当天 这个手机号联系过的所有电话号码
I want a print-out of all the calls made on that day from this number. OK?
- 可能得费些时间 - 不行 马上就要
- It'll take a while. - No, it won't. No.
你发现什么了？
What are you so excited about?
英国人撒尿是不会互相挨着的
Englishmen leave gaps when passing water.
- Helen好么？ - 挺好的 Francesca呢？
- How's Helen? - Fine. Francesca?
挺好
Fine.
- 好吧 其实我们分手了 - 那就不好呗
- Over, actually. - Not fine, then.
- Helen呢？ - 你问过一遍了
- Helen? - You've already asked me that.
你去哪？
Where are you going?
撒尿
Pee.
- 这才正常 - 你说什么？
- Every time. - What?
隔的越远越好
The biggest gap available.
- 啥？ - 男人撒尿的时候
- What? - Between men pissing.
我喜欢夜店 酒吧
I love pubs, bars.
你想怎样 Marlowe
What d'you want, Marlowe?
因为我喜欢爱嚼舌根的人
Because of the sawdust and what's in it.
窃窃私语 无心之谈
Dropped whispers, careless talk.
尽职的守卫就会在这种人身边出没
It's where a good guard puts himself- near to the sawdust.
你怎么看 Billy 关于Alex和Stevie
What do you reckon, Billy? Alex and Stevie.
我来告诉你大家是怎么传言的 他俩好不了多久
I'll tell you what the sawdust reckons. Won't last.
如果Stevie摆了Alex一道 难说她不会给你们事务所摆一道
And if Stevie walks on Alex, who's to say Stevie won't walk on the lot of you?
如果她真的摆你们事务所一道 我看你最好还是来我的事务所吧 Billy
And if Stevie walks on the lot of you, you'd be better off in my chambers, Billy.
个人愚见
In my humble opinion.
我打算跟Peter谈谈最低工资的问题 我认为这是我们应得的
Minimum wage. I'm going to ask Peter. I think we should have it.
- 你说的没错 不过 - 不过什么？
- I think you're right, but... - But?
交给我吧 我去跟他说
I'll do it. I'll tell him.
万一把他惹火了 你麻烦就大了
You've got a lot to lose if you get on the wrong side of him.
周六加班我也愿意 如果有需要请通知我
I'm really happy to work on Saturdays. Let me know if you need me.
还有一件事 最低工资 我可以不要
One other thing. The minimum wage. I don't want it.
不过Morag手头有点紧 我在想
But Morag, she's a bit hard up. I was thinking...
你不要工资 我们就能付她工资了
If we don't pay you, we can pay her.
年纪轻轻 胆量不小
You've got a lot of bollocks for a ten-year-old.
- 我听说你跟Stevie有点 - 有点什么？
- You and Stevie, I hear you're a bit... - Bit what?
- 有点情况 - 据我所知没什么情况啊
- Bit... iffy. - Completely fine last time I looked.
- 谁说我们怎么了？ - 我听到有人八卦了
- Who said we weren't? - I heard a whisper.
八卦？ 什么八卦？
A whisper? What kind of a whisper?
肯定是他们瞎说呢 Helen呢？
It's obviously wrong. And Helen?
据你所知 她还好吗？
Completely fine last time you looked?
- 这种事你可得理清楚啊 老兄 - 理不清楚
- Have to sort it out, mate. - I can't.
- 要珍惜眼前人 不要等失去了才... - 打住 Billy
- A bird in the hand... - Yeah, thanks, Billy.
Daniel还好么
Daniel?
- 真想知道？ - 当然了
- Are you interested? - Of course.
不要以为我当爸爸了就不是从前那个我了 Alex
I'm not a different person, Alex, just cos I've had a baby.
- 嗯... - 怎么了？
- Well... - What?
- 多少有点改变 - 好吧 多少有点
- A bit different. - A bit, maybe.
喝一杯？
Drink?
不了
Nah.
去吃点东西？
Bite to eat?
一会儿去酒吧看拳击比赛？
Bit of clubbing? Watch the fight later?
打算跟Rose安静的待在家 喂喂孩子
Quiet night in with Rose with a nice, big packet of Farley's rusks.
抱歉 失陪
Mea culpa.
一眨眼你都当爹了
You, a daddy.
再见 Billy
Night, Billy.
那个人离开大楼的时候我看的清清楚楚
I had a very clear view of the man leaving the building.
我认为我对他的描述完全精准
There's no doubt in my mind about the description I gave of him.
- 该我了 - 什么？
- My turn. - What?
上个证人是你盘问的
You did the last witness.
你认识Harry Fleck多久了？
How long have you known Harry Fleck?
什么？
What?
你是耳朵不好使 还是在故意耽误时间
Are you hard of hearing or just buying time?
- 我不认识他们 - 他们？
- I don't know them. - "Them"?
- 对 他们 - 我问的是"他" Harry
- Them. - I said "him". I said "Harry".
- 他们是谁们？ - Fleck一家
- What "them"? - The Flecks.
- 他们是什么人？ - 一个家族
- What are they? - Family.
什么样的家族？
What kind of family?
沉默是我的特长 Rush先生 我能陪你耗上一整天
I'm good with silence, Mr Rush. I can wait all day.
我从小就被我妈晾在婴儿车里 一晾就是一整天 没人跟我说话
My mum left me out in the pram all day when I was a baby. Just me and silence.
你要不要告诉陪审团 昨天你跟Harry Fleck在男厕所里
Do you want to tell the jury what you and Harry Fleck chatted about
- 谈了些什么？或者我来说？ - 我们当时在讨论案子
- in the gents toilet yesterday? Or shall I tell them? - We were talking about the case.
那关于案子你们讨论了什么
And what were you saying about the case?
Rush先生 你的沉默说明了一切
Mr Rush, your silence is eloquent and profound.
最后一个问题
One last question.
Fleck家买通你花了多少钱？
How much are the Fleck family paying you to do this?
- 你刚才 - 全是唬人的
- That was all... - Pure bluff.
我只知道 男人上厕所的时候绝对不会挨着别人的
All I know is that men do not stand next to each other in toilets
除非有事发生 或者 肯定有事发生
unless there's stuff going on or... stuff going on.
- 逞能啊 - 什么？\n说你呢 你没告诉当事人你会用这招
- Playing God.  - What?\nThat's what you do. You didn't tell the client you were gonna do that
- 你也没跟我商量好 - 当时正好时机来了
- and you didn't tell me. - I took the opportunity. It was offered.
你就是逞能了
You played God.
我们什么时候把当事人的话当回事过 Rose？
Since when has what the client says ever actually mattered, Rose?
你我辩护的时候从来就不是按指示来的\n再说这个案子根本没有指示
Since when have any of us been faithful to instructions?\nThere's no bloody instructions anyway.
胡编乱造才是最好的辩护方法
What we cook up between us is the best way around the problem.
而且几乎所有案子 当事人都是有罪的
And the problem, 99 times out of 100, is the client's guilt.
难道还真以为当事人是无辜的？
What d'you want? Innocent clients?
Billy 给我进来 马上
Billy. Get in here. Now.
你什么都不懂 你太自视过高了
You know nothing. You are nothing.
- Peter - 闭嘴 听我说
- Peter... - Shut it! Listen.
我的本职工作就是把握大局
It's my job to see the whole of the picture.
这次的案子比你想象的复杂的多
And that is much bigger than you'll ever know.
什么大局？
What picture?
这个案子的重点不在于你怎么辩护 也不在于判决结果
This case is not about you and it's not about the result!
而是关系到颜面 关系到对策 关系到我们事务所的未来
It's about face, it's about politics and it's about our future,
全被你搞砸了
and you fucked all three.
你说的话什么意思？ 什么颜面？
What are you talking about? Face?
这种大案子说穿了就是面子问题
This is big crime and big crime is all about face!
Alan Green想坐老大的位子 他想取代Harry Fleck
Alan Green wants to be president. He wants to be Harry Fleck.
这个时候他最不想看到的 就是半途杀出你这么个苏格兰律师
What he doesn't want is a Scotsman with a bee in his wig
在法庭上唧唧哇哇 说他是被Harry Green栽赃嫁祸
running the Greens and being fucking fitted up by Harry!
- 鸡蛋 面子 这案子就是加了五颗蛋的鸡蛋卷 - 但我们还是可以
- Egg. Face. It's a five-egg omelette!- But we can get off...
还能怎么样？ 如果Frank真的是被Harry嫁祸
What's that got to do with it? If Harry fitted up Frank,
人们就会觉得Green家族是打酱油的 打酱油的是做不了老大的
then the Greens look like amateurs. Amateurs don't run for president,
更别想从谁那里再捞到什么好处了
let alone get their cocks sucked by fat birds called Monica.
- 但是 - 如果真被判成是栽赃嫁祸了
- But... - If it comes down to it, bottom line,
Alan Green会牺牲Frank保全家族颜面
Alan Green would let Frank go down to save face.
面子才是最重要的
Face is everything.
改变辩护方法是我跟他商量好的
It was a joint idea. The change of tack.
她都看清形势了 她都懂了 所以她才帮你开脱
She sees it. She knows. That's why she's come in here to lie for you.
你要不是在带他辩护
Which I'd be deeply touched by if it weren't that you're supposed to be
- 我都要被你感动死了 Rose - 不是我带他 Peter 是平起平坐
- leading William Wallace here, Rose! - Equal partners, Peter. Equal.
沉着 可靠 稳重 低级律师的特质应有尽有 这话可是你说的
Stable. Reliable. Steady. Everything you need in a junior.
别用这种口气跟我说话
Don't talk to me like that!
跟谁都行 就是不许你在我跟前这么说Billy
Everyone else takes it round here. Not me, and not about him!
我就艹了
Fuck it.
有时候我看看飞虎队那些西装革履 头发梳得锃亮的警察
Sometimes I look at some sharp suit with wet hair from the Flying Squad
再看看被告席上的人 我就想
and then I'll lookt at whoever's in the dock and I think...
- 谁是谁？ - 谁是抢银行的 谁是警察
- "Which is which?" - "Blagger or copper?"
成年之后一个小小的职业选择 能彻底改变人生道路
One small career choice at 18 is the only difference.
长大后想与枪为伍 还是想半夜在查普顿闲逛 只需一个人生选择
Wanna play with guns, stay out late in Chapeltown? One choice.
- 当罪犯还是做警察 - 一旦做了选择 说到底其实怎么选都是一回事
- Blagger or copper? - Once they have made that choice, they're essentially the same thing.
- 都是50个人住一间 - 你又不知道个中区别
- 50 of each in a room... - You wouldn't know the difference.
- "看什么看？ 我吃定你了" - "我会让你蹲牢的"
- "You looking at me? I'll 'ave you." - "I'll 'ave you nicked."
确实说不清有什么区别
You wouldn't know the difference.
嘿
Hey.
- 事已至此了 - 什么？
- It's done now. - What?
你说Gary Rush被Fleck家买通的事
You connected Gary Rush to the Flecks.
木已成舟
Can't be undone.
案子只能照这条路走下去了
It's what the case is about now.
抱歉
Sorry.
不 你是对的 我们确实无时无刻不在逞能
No, you're right. We do play God all of the time.
谢谢
Thanks.
谢谢你在Peter面前帮我开脱
With McLeish.
我只不过是在力挺我的男人 请叫我Tammy
"Just standin' by my man. Just call me Tammy."
歌曲"Stand by Your Man" by Tammy Wynette
- 儿子一点都不像Frank Green - 对
- He doesn't look like Frank Green. - No.
更像Selsdon探长
More like Inspector Selsdon.
- 站在正义的一边 - 嗯
- The right side of the fence. - Hm...
对了
Yeah.
- 太好了 - 怎么了？
- Yes. - What?
坏人 警察 看不出来区别
Blagger. Copper. You wouldn't know the difference.
等我死了 让人把我的肝切开
When I've gone... I'm gonna have my liver cut up.
你们每个人都留一份
And I'm gonna leave you all a bit of it.
你们可以把它放在冰箱里
Then you can put it in the freezer
如果哪天酒瘾上来了 可以从冷藏室的把我的那块肝拿出来
and if you get caught short one night, you can go to the cold-box and wring yourself out a big Scotch
拧出一杯威士忌
from your very own piece of Peter McLeish.
这么一来 你们就永远不会忘记我了
That way, I'll always be with you.
这叫什么来着 足疗 对吧
It's erm, chiropody, innit?
你想说的是人体冷冻学吧
Cryogenics, you mean.
进门弄出这么大动静 Billy
That was quite an entrance, Billy.
那啥 我先去
Listen, I've got to erm...
- 我来是要你的允许 - 允许什么
- I've come to ask permission. - For what?
- 允许任何事情 - 任何事情？
- It's... everything. - "Everything"?
我们让Alan Green丢进颜面 他恨我们
Alan Green hates us for the loss of face.
- 所以呢？ - 什么能让他改变想法
- And? - What would bring him back?
- 他怎样才能回心转意？ - 你说说看
- What would turn him around? - You tell me.
掀牌 把整条链都拆穿
Pulling it down. The whole mountainside, the whole bloody edifice.
这案子不仅仅是Gary Rush跟Fleck家有瓜葛这么简单
It's not just Gary Rush and the Flecks in bed with each other.
还牵涉到警察参与 有来头 大官衔的上层警察
It's coppers. Big ones, with lots of shine on their shoulders.
我打算拆台 将这座势力网一网打尽
And I'm gonna blow it open, pull the whole stinking mountainside down.
Green家会回心转意的 因为等我拆完台 Green家就会成为新的势力网
The Greens will come back because they will be the new mountainside by the time I'm done.
但我需要你的允许
But I need your permission.
需要
Need?
想要
Want.
这事太重要了
This is everything.
- 成败在此一举 Billy - 我知道
- Make or break, Billy. - I know.
我爱你
I love you.
就这么办吧 管它的 尽管去
Do it. Fuck it. Do it.
她人呢 Stevie他妈的哪去了
Where is she? Where's bloody Stevie?
Guthrie先生
Mr Guthrie.
服警三十年是吧 探长
30 years in the force, Inspector.
Fleck家族掌控这个城市也差不多三十年了
About the same time as the Fleck family have been running this city.
- 掌控？ 我可不认为是掌控 - 我认为是
- Running? I wouldn't say running. - I would.
这不算是个问题 Guthrie先生
That's not a question, Mr Guthrie.
作为有组织的犯罪家族 他们算是颇有成就 对不对？
They're a successful organised-crime family. Yes or no?
对
Yes.
是最成功的 没有"朋友"的帮助
The best. You don't get to be the best for 30 years
没人能够维持一份成功三十年 "朋友"指的就是你们警察
without a little help from your friends. Which is where you come in.
这太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.
只跟一个犯罪家族保持友好往来 对你们有好处 因为关系稳定
It suits you to be cosy with one family because the boat doesn't rock
警察也得以在茶余饭后安心闲聊
and you can have cosy chats over breakfast, lunch and supper.
一切都井井有条 一切尽在掌握之中
Everything's tidy, everything's under control.
你敢夸这么大的口 希望你有证据 Guthrie先生
I hope you've got some evidence to back up your wildest dreams, Mr Guthrie.
恳请法官大人休庭两分钟？
Would Your Honour rise for two minutes?
- 为什么？ - 我想上厕所
- Why would I do that? - I need to relieve myself.
- 那你的低级律师可以代你继续 - 他是我的低级律师
- Then your junior can take over. - He is the junior.
而且我也想上厕所 法官大人
And I need to pee, too, Your Honour.
这个号码 Gary Rush报警前两分钟 他打过这个号码
This number. Two minutes before Gary Rush dialled 999 he called this number.
- 报警之后的两分钟 同样也打了这个号码 带手机了么 - 没带
- And the same number two minutes after the 999 call. Got your phone? - No.
擦
Shit.
喂
Hey.
法官回来了 Guthrie先生
The judge is coming back in, Mr Guthrie.
快接 快接
Please. Please.
- 喂 - 我就是打来问候一声
- Hello. - I just called to say I love you.
发自肺腑的深情问候
And I mean it from the bottom of my heart.
整座大山露出来了
The whole mountainside. The whole bloody thing.
- 你好 Marlowe先生 -  Tony
- Ah, Mr Marlowe. - Tony.
我帮您脱外套
Shall I take your coat, sir?
谢谢
Thank you.
你来
You do it.
是你想到这一招的 应该你来
You got us to here. It should be you.
你比我强
You're better than me at this.
各位陪审员
Members of the jury...
听说你那两个律师的表现不是很尽如人意啊
Word has it your filly and coat aren't acquitting themselves all that well.
所谓阴谋论 但他们没有证据
No evidence for the conspiracy theory.
Green家族不喜欢他们的辩护方式
The whole Green family hate what they're doing.
- 要我说你这次输定了 - 走着瞧
- I'd say you're on a loser. - We'll see.
再过一个小时左右就知道了 陪审团出判决用不了多久的
In about an hour from now. Shouldn't take the jury long.
三十年来 Selsdon探长都在利用Fleck家族的势力
For 30 years, Inspector Selsdon has been using the Fleck family
帮忙打理他的警察事务 更简单
to make the life of his police force simpler.
更透明 黑白两道相互通气
Clearer. He talks to the family Fleck. They talk to him.
犯罪依然存在 但是一切都在掌控之中
Crime goes on... but it's controlled.
事先说好 考虑周全
Agreed. Worked out.
最后也都能妥善解决
Managed.
Selsdon探长
Inspector Selsdon.
Harry Fleck
Harry Fleck.
看看他们
Look at them.
仔细看看他们
Go ahead. Look at them hard.
发现有什么区别吗？
Can you spot the difference?
我可看不出来
Because I can't.
- 花菜冷了 - 室温 先生
- Cauliflower's cold. - It's room temperature, sir.
- 什么？ - 花菜够室温了
- What? - The cauliflower's room temperature.
你再敢跟我抠字眼 我就用布丁勺子划开你的脖子
You split hairs with me, I'm gonna pick up that pudding spoon, open up your head
拿你的血当自助餐喝
and help myself to some of your hot cauliflower.
永远是这种感觉
It never changes.
等判决的时候 胃里有股难受劲
Waiting for the verdict. Here, in the stomach.
- 知道让我想起什么吗？ - 什么？
- You know what it reminds me of? - What?
孕吐
Morning sickness.
- 知道让我想起什么吗？ - 什么？
- You know what it reminds me of? - What?
第一次认识你的时候
The first time I met you.
胃里
Here.
翻江倒海
Stomach.
参与审理Green案的各位成员 请回到四号法庭
Will all parties in the case of Green return to Court 4?
你就爱耍这一套 是不是
You'll always do that, won't you?
哪一套？
What?
压力大的时候 无法维持镇定的时候 就会动用暴力
Reach for violence when you're wobbling, when you're under pressure.
- 陪审团归席了 马上出结果 - 够快啊 真够快
- Jury's coming back. Verdict coming in. - Quick. Very quick.
陪审团就本案是否达成一致判决？
Have you reached a verdict upon which all of you are agreed?
是
Yes.
被告谋杀罪名是否成立？
Do you find the defendant guilty or not guilty of murder?
不成立
Not guilty.
太好了 太好了 太好了
Yes! Yes! Yes!
真正无罪的人这时候通常会瘫倒 有罪之人才会高兴的冲着空气挥拳头
The innocent ones always collapse. The guilty ones punch the air.
可怜的空气 又一次被打了 恭喜你们
Poor old air, always being punched. Well done.
- 你们事务所的所作所为 - 怎么了？
- What you've just done, your chambers... - Yes?
- 挑起了一场战争 - 没错
- ...is to start a war. - Yes.
- 做得好 - 过奖
- Well done. - Thank you.
- 眼影真美 - 多谢夸奖
- Nice eye. - Thanks.
Billy和Rose绝对是一级棒的律师
Top class, Billy and Rose.
他们有多棒 我手下的所有律师就有多棒
What you got from them is what you'd get from all of my people.
还有一个问题 你跟Stevie 合作靠谱吗？
One thing. You and Stevie. You're solid, arent' you?
- 你们不会散伙吧 - 她跟我的一个律师好上了
- I mean there's no risk of you falling out? - She's sleeping with one of my boys.
- 那假如他俩散伙了 你们的生意也就散伙了？ - 他俩不会散伙
- If they fall out, do you fall out, too? - They won't fall out.
妥妥的 整件事都妥妥的
It's solid. The whole thing.
比你家后院的水泥还妥
Like the cement on your patio.
今后我们可以谈生意了
I think we can do business.
- Rose 嗨 - 你好 你想喝点什么？
- Rose, hi. - Hello. What do you want to drink?
- 嗯 - 给你
- Erm... - There you go.
- 这是什么？ - 每小时三块七 明天见 女生们
- What is it? - £3.70 an hour. Maana, ladies.
- 谢谢你帮我跟他要工资 Rose - 我还没说呢
- Thanks, Rose, for talking to him. - I didn't.
那是谁说的？
Who did, then?
你这样对她们两个都不公平
You're not being fair to either.
对Helen不公平 对Stevie也不公平
Helen, you're fucking over and Stevie, you're fucking over, too.
你应该一心一意 但你做不到 因为你惦记着Helen
You ought to be all first-flush and you're not cos you're up your arse over Helen.
但是跟Helen在一起 你又惦记着Stevie 来一支
With Helen, you're up your arse over Stevie. Cigarette?
- 我不抽烟 - 你再这样下去就要借烟消愁了
- No. I don't. - You will if you carry on like this.
你们这些人真好笑 个个都能说会道 口若悬河
You make me laugh, you lot. You're all brilliant gobs and all that,
但现实生活中遇到困难事 就傻眼了 是吧
but when it comes to the hard stuff- real, actual life - you can't hack it, can you?
只知道跑我跟前 唧唧歪歪 各种抱怨
You come to me and you blub and hum and hah,
让我知道你们脆弱的一面 然后再等我一番好言安慰
show me how soft your belly is, and what happens is I have to get a grip for you.
抱歉
Sorry.
我爱这片广场
I love this square.
- 真美 - 是
- Beautiful. - Yeah.
我去喝一杯
I'm gonna get a drink.
好 回见
Yeah, later.
不管了
Fuck it.
Helen
Helen.
我是Peter McLeish
It's Peter McLeish.
你好啊 美女
Hello, gorgeous.
好啊
Hello.
我去上个厕所
I'm er... I'm just going for a pee.
- 喝点什么？ - 谢谢 伏特加 加冰
- Can I get you a drink? - Thank you. Vodka. Ice.
我今天给一个流浪汉辩护了 挺可怜的 孑然一身
I represented a homeless man today. Sad. Adrift.
判决结果还行
We did OK.
我还没来得及说再见他就离开了
He'd left before I'd said goodbye.
我走的时候 看见他在咖啡馆里吃着肉末 喝着茶
When I left the court, I saw him again in a caff, eating mince, drinking tea.
挺同情他的 咖啡馆中的悲伤身影
And my heart went out to him. Sad man in caff.
他怎么就从一个小宝宝 长大之后
I mean, what had brought him from little baby
沦落到身处利兹最廉价的咖啡馆吃着廉价的食物
to mince and cups of tea in the cheapest caff in Leeds?
我透过玻璃看着他
And I watched him through the glass
还看到很多人走进咖啡馆
and a whole load people went into the caff
轻拍他的背 不断的打着招呼
and they patted my sad man on the back and hello'd and hello'd.
那时候的他看上去一点都不悲伤
And he wasn't sad at all.
突然我感到自己又傻又孤独
And I suddenly felt... lonely and foolish.
这么轻易的就会爱上旁人的孤独
It's so easy to fall in love with other people's sadness.
再见了 Alex
Goodbye, Alex.
Helen
Helen.
你是否改信基督教？
Do you turn to Christ?
我改信基督教
I turn to Christ.
你是否忏悔你的罪过？
Do you repent of your sins?
我忏悔我的罪过
I repent of my sins.
你是否弃恶从善
Do you renounce evil?
我弃恶从善
I renounce evil.
让你的爱将他围绕
Surround this child with your love.
保护他远离邪恶
Protect him from evil.
给予他神圣的灵魂
Fill him with your holy spirit.